Pankaj Bhambhani

Student at University of Massachusetts, Amherst

Phone:

+17814922535

Address:

Amherst, MA - 01002

Website:

pankajb64.blogspot.in

Email:

pankajb64@gmail.com

* EDUCATION

September 2016 - September 2018 University of Massachusetts Amherst Master of Science in Computer Science

Courses Taken : Machine Learning

2009 - 2013

DA-IICT

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information and Communication Technology,

CPI 8.6/10

Relevant Courses Taken - Algorithms, Data Structures, Computer Networks, Databases, Operating Systems, Systems Software, Cryptography, Security Protocols, Graph Theory, Computer Organisation, Natural Computing

2007 - 2009

Saint Xavier's High School, Adipur, (Gujarat)

HSC (Higher Secondary)

Higher Secondary Percentage - 91.85 % (aggregate)

2005-2007

Saint Xavier's High School, Adipur, (Gujarat)

SSC (Secondary Education)

Secondary Education Percentage - 91.08 % (aggregate)

* EXPERIENCE

July 2013 - May 2016 (2 years 10 months) Play Games 24x7 Private Limited

Software Development Engineer

Worked as SDE for RummyCircle.com, one of the major products of Games24x7. Involved in Full Stack Web Development.

Technologies - Java, Spring, Spring Security, Jersey (JAX-RS), Hbase, Ehcache, Terracotta, Redis, Akka, MySql, Hibernate, MyBatis, Node.js.

Accomplishments include horizontal scaling of distributed caches using Ehcache and Terracotta, building Restful Web Services and strengthening application security using Spring Security.

December 2012 -May 2013 (6

months)

Oracle

Interim Automation Engineer

Worked as an Automation Engineer with Merchandise Operations Management (MOM) Team at Oracle Retail on products like RMS (Retail Merchandising System) and Allocation. Used technologies like **QTP** (**Quick Test Professional**) for RMS and **Selenium Webdriver** for scripting and execution of test cases.

May 2012 -August 2012 (4 months) **KDE**

Software Developer

Integrated features of Facebook into KDE's micro blogging client, Choqok (Under the program **Google Summer of Code 2012**).

Technology used: KDE4 based on Qt (C++ based GUI Framework).

Link - https://github.com/pankajb64/chogok-facebook

*PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Currently pursuing my Masters at UMass Amherst, I have three years of Software Development Experience. I have worked as an SDE for Play Games 24x7 Pvt. Ltd., I did my B.Tech from DA-IICT, have worked as Software Developer for KDE as a part of Google Summer of Code and Automation Engineer Intern at Oracle Retail. I have interests in Machine Learning, Algorithm Design & Analysis, Software Security, Computer Networking, and I am looking to work in these areas.

May 2011 - July 2011 (3 months) **KDE**

Software Developer

Build base KDE library, namely KFbAPI, which formed the ground for Integrating Facebook Features for Choqok (which was done next summer under Google Summer of Code 2012).

Technology used: **KDE4 based on Qt** (C++ based GUI Framework).

* PROJECTS

October 2012 to November 2012 Certified Electronic Mail

http://slidesha.re/certemail

Studied the properties and commented on possible (desirable + implementable) combinations for a Certified Electronic Mail System for providing Security to Electronic Mail with a focus on improving security features of existing widely used security protocols: S-Mime, PGP. Team Size - 5

Link to Presentation - http://slidesha.re/certemail

October 2012 to November 2012 Synthesize Reactions using Chemical Computing Constructs

https://github.com/pankajb64/reaction-synthesizer

Analyzed how various computing constructs could be synthesized using appropriate chemical reactions and wrote a model class for the same..

Link to project source - https://github.com/pankajb64/reaction-synthesizer

Technology - Java. Team Size - 3

January 2012 to April 2012 Ecodena

https://github.com/pankajb64/ecodena

Created an Online Judge System, which attempts to motivate novice users towards problem solving by providing comprehensive error reporting and a variety of tutorials.

Technology: Django (based on Python). Team Size – 9 Link to project source - https://github.com/pankajb64/ecodena

April 2015 to May 2015

Duckworth Lewis (D/L) Calculator for Android

https://github.com/pankajb64/duckworth-lewis-d-l-calculator-android

Designed and Built Duckworth Lewis Calculator - an Android application which lets users predict scores and results in rain interrupted cricket matches.

Technology: Android.

Link to play store app - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fl.dlc

* SKILLS

Interest Areas - Software Engineering, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Software Security, Natural Computing, Computer Networking, Databases, Artifical Intelligence, Machine Learning

Programming Languages - Java, C, MySQL (Familiarity with: Scala, Python, Bash, Ruby, PgSQL, Qt, C#, JavaScript)

Software Testing Technologies - Selenium WebDriver, QTP, Cucumber, Capybara, RSpec **Development Technologies** - Spring, Spring Security, Hbase, Ehcache, Terracotta, Redis, Akka, SQL, JDBC, Hibernate, MyBatis, Node.js. Apache Tomcat, HTML, CSS, XML, jQuery(basic), Django, Rails, Android.

Software Tools Used - Git, SVN, Ant, Maven, MySQL, Eclipse, Android Studio, Wireshark, Vim